reachlocal.com 2019-03-06

# Privacy Policy | ReachLocal

ReachLocal, Inc. (“ReachLocal”, “we”, “us”) is committed to respecting your privacy and recognizes your need for appropriate protection and management of any personally identifiable information (“Personal Information”) you share with us. ReachLocal has established this Privacy Policy to let you know what information we may collect from you on the publicly available portion of Reachlocal.com (the “Site”) and through various other interactions with you, and how we may use and share that information. Please take a moment to review the terms of our Privacy Policy. By using the Site and/or providing us Personal Information, you agree to accept the terms of our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Site or provide us any Personal Information. This Privacy Policy applies to information that we collect on the Site and to information which we may collect by other “offline” means, including, without limitation, sales calls and other business transactions. A description of the information we collect on behalf of our advertiser clients through our advertising services is set out in our [Notice of Marketing Practices.](https://www.reachlocal.com/us/en/legal/reachlocal-notice-marketing-practices)

###  Personal Information

####  Information We May Collect

Personal Information means any information that may be used to identify an individual, including, but not limited to, a first and last name, a home, business, or other physical address, a phone number, and an email address. We collect Personal Information from our Site users and customers only when such information is voluntarily provided to us, including, without limitation, in connection with inquiries about our services through the “Contact Us” page, as part of signing up for our email subscriptions, or in the process of your business transactions with us. To make our content more relevant to you, we may also ask for information about your present place of employment, such as company name, size, industry sector and number of employees. Of course, if you send us an email in connection with an inquiry about a job listed on the “Careers” page, we may also store the Personal Information provided in connection with that inquiry.

We also offer a variety of email subscriptions where you can get information about online marketing and promotions and special offers. You can [subscribe for such emails](http://go.reachlocal.com/manage-subscription-signup.html) and you can [manage your email preferences ](http://go.reachlocal.com/manage-subscription-signup.html). If you become a customer of ReachLocal, we will always retain the right to email you regarding the Site or services that we’re providing to you.

####  How We May Use Your Information

If you provide us with Personal Information, we may retain and use that information for several purposes, including facilitating and otherwise addressing your inquiry, request, subscriptions, or business transactions and relationship with ReachLocal. For example, we may use your Personal Information in order to respond to your questions or requests for information about ReachLocal. We may also use Personal Information to ensure compliance with our policies and applicable law.

####  With Whom We May Share Your Information

We may sometimes use other businesses to perform certain services for us, such as maintaining the Site and our e-mail services and processing inquiries. We may provide Personal Information to those businesses when that information is necessary for them to complete a requested transaction or otherwise perform their duties. ReachLocal will take reasonable steps to ensure that these third-party service providers are obligated to protect Personal Information on ReachLocal’s behalf. ReachLocal will not sell or share your Personal Information with any unaffiliated third parties for marketing purposes. In the event that ReachLocal or all of its assets are acquired, all of the data collected by ReachLocal through the Site and through other means and services provided by ReachLocal would be among the transferred assets. We reserve the right to disclose such information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact, or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) our rights or property, other visitors, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. We also reserve the right to disclose such information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it.

###  Non-Personal Information

From time to time, we may collect general, non-personal, statistical information about the use of the Site, such as from what sites visitors are coming from when they visit our Site, when they first visited our Site, their IP address, how many visitors visit a specific page on the Site, how long they stay on that page and which hyperlinks, if any, they “click” on. We may use the IP address to infer information about such visitor, including its company, city and state. We collect this information through the use of “cookies” and other tracking technologies, which are discussed in greater detail below. We collect this information in order to determine which areas of the Site are most popular and to enhance the Site for visitors. We may group this information into aggregate visitor data in order to describe the use of the Site to our existing or potential business partners, sponsors, advertisers, or other third parties, or in response to a government request. However, please be assured that this aggregate data will in no way personally identify you or any other visitors to the Site.

####  Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

Some of our web pages utilize “cookies” and other tracking technologies.  A cookie is a small text file that a website transfers to an individual’s web browser and is stored on the device.  Cookies and other tracking technologies may record information such as URL and domain requested, referral URL, Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser software and operating system types, clickstream patterns, and dates and times that our Site is accessed.  We, and/or our third-party advertising service providers, may place cookies or similar files on your computer for security purposes (such as authentication), to facilitate site navigation and to personalize your experience while visiting our Site.  Cookies allow us to collect technical and navigational information, such as browser type, time spent on our Site and pages visited (these types of cookies are typically referred to as “Session Cookies”).  We also use cookies that enable us to serve advertisements of our products and services, including special offers, when you visit other websites (these cookies may be referred to as “Advertising Cookies”).

We do not obtain, store or maintain any Personal Information about you through our use of cookies (either the Session Cookies or the Advertising Cookies).  Also, we do not link the information we store in cookies to any Personal Information you may submit while on the Site. However, we reserve the right to use IP addresses and other tracking technologies to identify a visitor only when we feel it is necessary to enforce compliance with the Site’s policies, to protect the Site, our customers, or others, or when we believe in good faith that the law requires it.  

You may set most browsers to notify you if you receive a cookie, or you may choose to block cookies with your browser.  However, please be aware that some features of the Site may not function properly or may be slower if you refuse cookies.  While the Site does not currently respond to ‘Do Not Track’ signals submitted by your browser, you can opt out of any of the Advertising Cookies at any time by simply visiting <http://www.reachlocal.com/opt-out> to adjust your preferences.  You can find out more about your ‘Do Not Track’ options, please visit [http://www.allaboutDNT.com](http://www.allaboutdnt.com/)..

If you have any questions regarding ReachLocal’s privacy practices, you are encouraged to contact ReachLocal at [privacy@reachlocal.com.](mailto:privacy@reachlocal.com)

###  Links to Other Sites; Public Venues test

Please be aware that when you are on the Site, you could be directed to other sites that are beyond our control via hyperlinks. For example, if you choose to use the ReachLocal Directory at the Site, you may be sent to a third party website if you click on a hyperlink. These other websites may send their own cookies to visitors, collect data, or solicit Personal Information. The privacy policies of these other sites may be significantly different from this Privacy Policy. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of these other sites and cannot guarantee the security of any of your Personal Information collected there.

###  Security

The security of your Personal Information is important to us. We take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of data. These include internal reviews of our data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures, as well as physical security measures to guard against unauthorized access to systems where we store personal data. We restrict access to personal information to ReachLocal employees, contractors and agents who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our services. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and may be subject to discipline, including termination and criminal prosecution, if they fail to meet these obligations. For more information visit the [Security](http://www.reachlocal.com/security) page.

###  Account

If you become a customer, you will be able to access ReachCentral™, our advertiser portal, through the Site with a unique password. Your access to and use of ReachCentral, together with all other aspects of your relationship as customer of ReachLocal will be governed by your agreement with ReachLocal. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your password and account, and are fully responsible for all activities that occur under your password or account.

###  Children’s Privacy

This Site is not intended for use by children under 13. We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from anyone under 13 years of age. If we become aware that we have unknowingly collected Personal Information from a child under the age of 13, we will make commercially reasonable efforts to delete such information from our database.

###  Changes to Our Privacy Policy

The terms of this Privacy Policy may change from time to time. We will notify you of any material changes to this Privacy Policy by posting a notice on the homepage of the Site for a reasonable period of time after such changes are made that this Privacy Policy has been updated and by changing the “Last Modified” date at the top of this Privacy Policy. We encourage you to check this page periodically for any changes. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes.

###  Governing Law

ReachLocal makes no representation that this Privacy Policy and such practices comply with the laws of any other country. Visitors who use the Site and reside outside the United States do so on their own initiative and are responsible for compliance with local laws, if and to the extent local laws are applicable. If you reside outside of the United States, by using our Site, you consent to the transfer and use of your information outside your country.

###  Contacting Us

If you have any comments or questions regarding our Privacy Policy, please contact us at [privacy@reachlocal.com](mailto:privacy@reachlocal.com), or at our contact information below.

ReachLocal, Inc.  
21700 Oxnard Street, Suite 1600  
Woodland Hills, CA 91367  
888-466-2520
